Hubungi

+6283878710816 (Home) taufiqhidayaht@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/taufiqhidayah (LinkedIn)

taufiqhidayah.github.io/ (Portfolio) github.com/taufiqhidayah (Portfolio)

Keahlian Teratas

Agile Methodologies
Front-end Development
Back-End Web Development

Languages

Bahasa Jawa (Native or Bilingual) Bahasa Indonesia (Native or Bilingual)

Bahasa Inggris (Professional Working)

Certifications

CSS Essential Training

Learning Node.js

Programming Foundations: Software Testing/QA

Getting Started in User Experience

Honors-Awards

Web Design LKS Kediri Regional

Delphi Application

3rd Hackaton Tokopedia

DBS Live More Society: Developer Challenge 2

Indonesia Next Apps 4.0 – Samsung SDK Challenge

Taufiq Hidayah

Engineer at AIA Singapore

Indonesia

Ringkasan

Develop software?

Let's discuss and contribute together.

Building software is not just digitizing the system. but with the software, we can help many people.

Hello. My name is Taufiq, a person who likes to learn and explore new things, likes traveling. enjoy solitude with the sounds of nature and environmentalist.

I have experience working as a mobile developer cross platforms mobile app using React Native, Web platforms using (ReactJs, Redux, antd), Backend (NodeJs, Sequelize, MsSql), and have experience using: Git Control Flow, Docker, and Jira Management Tools

In my spare time, I like to do sports activities at the fitness center, running around the housing complex and like to do cooking.

Feel free to reach me:)

Pengalaman

Dedycated.Inc
Frontend Developer
Oktober 2021 - Present (7 bulan)

AIA Singapore

2 tahun 3 bulan

Engineer

Februari 2021 - Present (1 tahun 3 bulan)

iRecruit:



This project is part of the "MyBusiness" in AIA Singapore Agency Digital Blueprint, whereby one of the focus areas will be the recruitment and onboarding experience for agency leaders and their candidates.

Objective: To provide an end-end paperless recruitment & on-boarding experience through a holistic integrated digital recruitment platform for agency leaders, their candidates and AIAS staff.

Job Description:

- Developing new feature of iRecruit Application
- Handling Backend of iRecruit using NodeJs
- Handling Front-End Web/Mobile using ReactJS/React Native
- Responding to deliver feature/report by user on time base on Agile Methodology with Jira Tools

DDS 2.0 ReactJs UI Component

This project is creating reusable UI component that can be used in AIA Web Frontend project

Job Description / Experience :

- Creating reuseable components using typescript
- Creating unit testing UI Component using Jest
- Using SCSS, Bootstrap as styling standart
- Using stroybook to create UI Component documentation

Software Engineer Internship

Februari 2020 - Februari 2021 (1 tahun 1 bulan)

- Develop new feature front end web of iRecruit App
- Continuously improve by capturing and analyzing and testing of iRecruit APPS
- Collaboration with team to match the requirement.

Guide Santai

React Native Developer

September 2021 - Oktober 2021 (2 bulan)

Switzerland

Binus Malang Computer Club

Founder

Oktober 2019 - Oktober 2020 (1 tahun 1 bulan)

Initializing the computer club organization on campus, with the aim that students can learn a lot about computational thinking, and can solve problems through code.

Binus University

2 tahun

Duta Binusian

Agustus 2019 - Desember 2019 (5 bulan)

As a BINUS student ambassador, I was assigned to be a mentor, a buddy to teach some particular subjects, help the lecture and help and encourage BINUS students who have problems with their academics.

Resource Development - HIMFO (Informatics Engineering Student Association)

Januari 2019 - Desember 2019 (1 tahun)

I was assigned to help students find relationships and connections with people who are experienced in a field to hold collaborative activities with the informatics engineering student association

Research And Development Team - HIMFO (Informatics Engineering Student Association)

Januari 2018 - Januari 2019 (1 tahun 1 bulan)

As a Research and Development team, I was assigned to assist students in developing ideas and implementation in the form of applications

SMA Negeri 1 Malang

Programming Mentor

Juli 2018 - Desember 2019 (1 tahun 6 bulan)

Malang dan Sekitarnya, Jawa Timur, Indonesia

as an extracurricular mentor I was assigned to help high school students learn the basics of computer programming and teach how to make applications / games.

web and mobile-based.

Using C language, code.org, html / css and Android Java

Google Developers

DSC Lead Universitas Bina Nusantara

Februari 2018 - Juli 2019 (1 tahun 6 bulan)

Google Developers program for university students, designed to help them build their mobile and web development skills and knowledge. It is open to any student, ranging from novice developers who are just starting, to advanced developers who want to further their skills. It is intended to be a space for students to learn and collaborate as they solve mobile and web development problems.

AdaPasar.com Android Developer September 2017 - Oktober 2017 (2 bulan) Malang Area, East Java, Indonesia

- > Create Tracking Maps Android
- > Payment System Method

Indonesia Mobile-app Academy (IMASTUDIO)
Assistant Trainner
September 2016 - Maret 2017 (7 bulan)
Jl. Anggrek Rosliana no 12A RT 3/RW 9, Kemanggisan Slipi Palmerah,

Mobile App

Jakarta Barat

Pendidikan

Universitas Bina Nusantara (Binus) S.Kom, Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)